In Maureen's section, we learned of different ways to deal with null data,
在 Maureen 的课上 我们已经学了处理空值的不同方法
such as filtering out records that are null, removing fields in whole, or
例如 过滤掉是 null 的记录 删掉整个字段
imputing in various ways.
或者以一些方法进行估算
My thought is that since the percentage of missing values in the number of
既然 voicemail（语音邮件）字段缺失值数量的百分比
voicemail fields is so high at 74%, we shouldn't filter those
高达 74% 所以我的想法是不去过滤掉记录
out since it would actually just reduce our data set way too much.
因为过滤记录实际上删除了太多的数据集记录
As well if we imputed such a large percentage of missing records,
如果我们用缺失值数量百分比那么大的数据集去进行估算
it will most likely cause a bias in our data set.
这可能会造成数据集中出现偏差
So my thought is to simply just, we should ignore it for the analysis.
所以我认为我们应该在分析中忽略空值
The way we're going to do that is, let's go back to our workflow and
我们要做的事是回到工作流程
just bring in the select tool to just simply deselect that field.
拖拽 select (选择)工具然后直接取消选择这个字段
So we can bring in that select tool in our stream already,
所以我们可以拖拽 select (选择)工具到流程中
go to the number of voicemail field, and simply deselect it.
转到 voicemail（语音邮件）字段 直接取消选择这个字段
Now we have our two other fields that we need to deal with our null records for
现在我们还有两个需要处理空值的字段
the total night calls, and the total day calls fields.
是 total night calls（晚上电话合计）字段和 total date calls（日期电话合计）字段
Both of those percentages were at 2%.
它们两个的缺失值数量百分比都是2%
So my though is that we should just simply filter those records out since
所以我认为我们应该直接过滤掉这些记录
2% is not going to cause to many records to go away for the total data set.
因为 2% 不会造成数据集中丢失太多记录
So now what we need to do is remove those two different
所以现在我们要做的是删除这两个
fields that have null records within that 2% of our field.
空值百分比是 2% 的字段中的空值
So we're going to use a filter tool to do this.
所以现在我们使用 filter（过滤）工具去做
I'm going to drag this right in between our stream.
我拖拽 filter（过滤）工具到流程的右边
We're then going to state a custom filter and
接下来我们讲讲 custom filter（自定义过滤器）
this custom filter is going to tell us two things.
custom filter（自定义过滤器）在这里说明两件事
The first thing is we do not want nulls that are inside of our total night calls
第一件事是我们不想在 total date calls（日期电话合计）字段
field, and we don't want nulls that are inside of our total day calls field.
和 total night calls（晚上电话合计）字段中有空值
So, the way we're going to do this custom filter is first,
所以首先在 custom filter（自定义过滤器）中要做的是
we're going to go to our functions tab.
转到 functions（功能）选项面板
We're then going to go to our operators and state not.
接着我们选择 operators 选项和 not 选项
The whole reason we want that not first,
我们首先要选的是 not 00:01:51,090 --&gt; 00:01:54,760 是因为我们要继续下拉列表选择 test 选项然后输入 IsNull
So, what this statement right here just says, is not null.
所以右边的表述框里写的意思是去掉空值
Then that v that's currently right there,
接着我们看到这里右侧有 v 字母
is that variables that we want to place inside of there.
这表示我们想要放到这里的变量
So the first one we need to state is total days called.
我们需要的第一个变量是 total days called（白天电话合计）
So what this whole part says right here,
所以这个部分表示
is we do not want nulls within this total days called field.
我们不想在 total days called（白天电话合计）字段中有空值
Everything that is not null is going to come outside as true value.
所有不是空值的值会作为真值输出到外面
Anything that is null within that field is going to come outside as false value.
所有在这个字段里是空值的值会作为假值输出到外面
We need to now do this for both of our fields, so
我们要在这两个字段里做这样的操作
I'm going to do an and statement in between.
我要在两个字段之间写一个 And 语句
And now I'm going to just manually type out the is null,
现在我在这里手动输入 Is Null
because in my opinion it's just a little bit quicker to write it out.
因为我认为这会更快一点
So now he says is not null for now our total evening calls.
现在这个没有空值的对象是 total evening calls(晚上电话合计)
When I hit run now, we should see that we have totally clean records
当我点击运行时 应该能看到完整的清洗过的记录
outside this true and as well inside this interactive browse.
被输出到T这边和交互式浏览界面
Because within this interactive browse,
在这个交互式浏览界面中
we can now see that there's no percentage missing
现在可以看到在 total day's call (白天电话合计)字段
In that total day's call field as well as the total evening call field.
和 total evening call（晚上电话合计）字段中没有缺失值的百分比记录了
All of those no records actually went outside this false value over here.
所有没有值的记录实际上被输出到这里的 false value F侧
And if we drag over to our field we can see total day calls are no over here
如果我们向右滑动 能看到这里没有 total day calls(白天电话合计)
as well as total night calls as well.
和 total night calls（晚上电话合计）
That's exactly what I was expecting.
这是我所期望的结果
After running this, we see that on the false set, we have 95 records which
在进行这个操作之后 可以看到在假值集中有 95 条记录
represent the records that do have null values in either one of the fields.
这表明在这两个字段中存在空值记录
The true data is now our cleaned up data set, with no null values.
真值集现在是清洗过的数据集 不包含空值
So what we should do is we should save off this data set with an output
我们要做的是把这个数据集用
data tool.
output data (输出数据)工具进行保存
So let's delete these two tools now because we know that our data set
现在我们删除这两个工具
is clean.
因为我们的数据集已经被清洗好了
So let's now bring in an output data tool.
接下来我们拖拽 output data (输出数据)工具
Bring it in after the true result.
把它放在真值结果的右边
And let's save this off so
我们保存下真值文件
we can use it again continuing forward in further analysis.
那么可以再次使用它继续进行后面的分析
And we no longer have to bring in a select tool and a filter tool.
我们不必再拖拽 select tool(选择工具)和 filter tool(过滤工具)
So hit the drop down menu, go to file browse.
点击这里的下拉菜单 选择文件浏览
I'm going to say that this file's a YXDB file, and
选择 YXDB 类型进行保存
I'm going to call it churn data cleaned.
给这个文件命名为 churn data cleaned
You can call it whatever you would like and
你可以按照你的喜好命名
save it whatever folder you would like.
按照你的喜好放在任何文件夹保存
I'm going to hit run, that file is now going to be saved out and
点击运行 这个文件将会被保存下来
I'm going to now, in the work flow bring in just this now input data so
我现在可以在工作流程中直接拖拽刚才的输入数据
I don't have to bring in a select and a filter every time to clean up this file.
我不需要每次再拖拽 select tool(选择工具)和 filter tool(过滤工具)去清洗文件了